Within Word, as well as creating
documents from scratch, you can use a
wide range of pre formatted templates
to insert your information into.
As you can see with the letter on
the screen in front of me, this
is a plain blank document that
I have then inserted all of the
information relating to a letter.
However, if I wish to enhance the
document, make it look more professional,
I could format that and edit it add
images add charts, tables, shading, and
various other elements into the letter.
Or alternatively, I could
access a preformatted template,
which will have all of that
information and formatting applied.
So just to access the template files, I
would just click on the File menu, select
New and then I'm brought to the screen
with a wide range of templates available.
So there are some templates on the
initial page, but you can access specific
templates such as business templates,
cards, flyers, letters educational types
of documents, resumes, and cover letters.
So if I just select a letter and
then from the list, I can pick a
specific letter just to demonstrate.
As you can see this has already been
provided with, formatting, there are
spaces  for images, the text is broken
up into paragraphs and sections.
There's a whole section relating to
the address, phone, email and website
address and I could copy  that information
from that letter into that document.
One of the things to bear in mind,
if you wish to insert specific images
and change the content of your letter
to a certain style and in a certain
way, you will be better off using a
blank document because the template
already has the formatting applied.
It is structured, has different
sections within it, and it can be
difficult to change those sections
without disrupting the layout
and presentation of the template.
So, if you need to insert images,
charts, tables, and various other
elements within a letter, and you
need to have full control over that.
You will be far better using an
existing document that you've created.
And then you can save that as a
template rather than use a preformatted
template, which will have all of
the formatting already applied.